Welcome back, scum!
Kaiji returns to the silver screen!
And we give you loyal anime watchers a sneak peek!
Kaiji's rival, the young elite Ichijou!
In FKMT's works depicting the inner working of the heart,
he is second only to fake Akagi as a moe character!
Playing Ichijou is...
The Bog's guaranteed not to pay out.
Yusuke Iseya!
You've got to see his sneers, his shouts, his laughs!
It's great. Compared to other dramas, everything can change in a split second.
Shit, shit, shit!
Or that "eh" when he realizes it's over.
That's the kind of thing you can't see in other movies.
Don't miss Iseya playing the moe-moe Ichijou!
Kaiji 2: Jinsei Dakkai Game, this November 5th!
Kaiji and Ichijou both anticipate!
カイジ　一条　それぞれの思惑
Who will be blessed by fate!?
天が味方するのは どっちだ
I'll hit it! I'll hit it!
当てる　当てる　当てる ７億！
I'll hit the 700-million jackpot!
Yeah, that's it!
そうだ その意気だ
いったれや
Go for it!
The Might of Benjamin
Win what I lost!
俺の分まで勝ってくれ
ヘヘヘ　当たるわけがない
無駄金だ
There's no way you'll win.
You're wasting your money.
Play as much as you want, Kaiji. I don't mind.
いいぞ カイジ
好きなだけ挑戦して
Go for it!
No matter how hard you struggle, you can never beat me.
どうあがこうと勝てやしないんだ
お前は俺に
Here it comes!
きた！
それも２段目だ　２段目
He's in the second tray again!
The second tray!
ハハハ　そう ２段目
Yes, the second tray.
The second tray is the problem for him.
この２段目が まさに問題なのだ
What a clever trick, if I do say so myself!
我ながら感心するぜ　自らのツキ
Oh well, I guess I'm just lucky.
何しろ まったくの偶然
He's the one who tilted the building somehow to begin with.
仕方なく 半ば一か八かで
奴がビルを倒して作った
奥への傾斜に
I just added to it.
こっちも かぶせていっただけ
That double tilt kills every ball before they make it out of the second tray!
その過剰な奥への傾斜で
何とか２段目までで
玉を殺そうと目論んだだけ
How deliciously unexpected!
それが思いもかけず
完璧 最高の
あんばいになってくれた
It's truly the best thing I could have done!
When the balls lose their momentum, they can no longer climb against the double tilt!
つまり銀玉の完成
回転力が失われてくると
二重の奥への傾斜が ものをいい
もう上らない
They fall to their deaths in the hole furthest back!
玉は最下点
一番奥の穴で ほとんど死ぬ
But some balls have the energy left to climb just a little.
しかし時には最後の力で
その傾斜を上る玉もある
In the first tray, the next hole is a winner.
１段目の場合
最下点の次は当たり穴
So one of every few balls makes it through.
だから 何玉かに１玉
２段目に行く
But in the second tray, balls which avoid the depths find only another loser!
しかし２段目の場合
最下点を過ぎた玉が
よろよろと向かう先はハズレ穴
It can't make it to the winner!
当たり穴には絶対 届かない
The double tilt kills them all!
必殺 最強の二重傾斜　ヘヘヘ
Here we go!
Go for it!
いけ！抜けろ
Miss the hole!
You fool!
バカが　気がつかんか まだ
Haven't you realized yet!?
All right! Go for it!
よし よし　いけ いけ
フフフ　ゼロか
Zero...
They have zero capacity for learning...
どいつもこいつも学習能力ゼロ
ああ ３段目に行かないってことに
対して何の疑問もわかないのか
They aren't even wondering why he's never making it to the third tray.
They aren't questioning that at all.
わかないのか 何の疑問も
Those morons.
アホタレ　分かんねえのか
Doesn't he get it? It'll never make it past the second tray!
入らねえんだよ ２段目の穴は
He's wasting his time!
無意味ってことだ
いくらねばっても　ハハハ
Fine, I'll tell you. Since we've both tilted it inward—
教えてやる
つまり俺とお前の奥への傾斜が…
知っている
あ…
I know.
I know that, Ichijou.
そんなことは知っている 一条
But there's something that's going to surprise you.
びっくりするぜ たぶん
あ…
The other thing this double tilt has caused.
二重の奥への傾斜がもたらした
もう１つの現象
Once you see it...
そいつを目の当たりにしたら
Impossible! You're not even making any sense!
バカが
何をわけの分からないことを
Don't try and fool me into thinking you've got something up your sleeve!
意味ありげな構えや
かっこつけなんかしても無駄だ
Look!
その証拠に見ろ
玉は着々と減り続けている
You're losing balls as fast as you can shoot them!
You've only got 5 left out of the 10 million you just borrowed!
頼みの1000万も残り500 半分
Only half!
You're out of tricks now!
種切れさ
お前の小細工 手品の種は
ハハハ　なるほど 手品か
そうするか いっそ
Tricks, huh.
You want tricks? I'll give you tricks.
Endoh.
遠藤さん
セロハンテープ持ってないか
Do you have any scotch tape?
I think I've got some in my briefcase.
ええ　たぶん カバンに
貸してくれ
Gimme some.
You heard him.
おい
はあ
Here.
ほれ
Ichijou.
一条　最後の最後に見せてやろう
I've got one last little magic spell to show you.
俺の とびっきりの秘術 魔法を
I guess I can't talk too much shit.
まあ偉そうには言えないか
Being able to do this is pure luck.
何せ これは まったくの偶然
計算外の現象
It's not any talent of mine, it's more like a blessing.
神がかり的幸運　俺の力じゃない
言うなら天の力
勝負のあやってやつだ
It's like divine power is controlling our match.
え？
な… 何をする
What are you doing!?
There we go.
完成だ
If I put this blind up like this...
この目隠しが秘訣
こうしておいて しばらく打つ
And keep shooting...
It's a miracle!
すると あーら不思議
霊験あらたか
福沢諭吉の威光が道を開く
The might of Benjamin opens me a path!
Heaven places no man above another,
｢天は人の上に人を造らず
人の下にも人を造らず｣
no man below another!
What I'm going on about is that the rise and fall of men is chance alone!
この御託の意味は 要するに
人間の浮き沈みはチャンス次第
Even a fool or scum has a chance to win!
バカでもクズでも
チャンスを生かせば勝者　フンッ
And that chance is never too far away!
そして そのチャンスは
案外 身近に落ちている
Focus!
目を凝らし諦めなければ
蘇生さえ可能
Never give up, and even rebirth is possible!
Meaning... Even these dead balls can spring back to life!
つまり一度 死んだ玉さえ生き返る
What's he talking about?
おいおい　何言い出すんだよ
What's with that blind!?
意味ねえよ 目隠しなんかしたって
It's no fun watching when you can't see!
第一 見えなきゃ興味半減だ
Yeah!
そうだ
見せろ　見せろよ
Let us watch!
Hold on just a second longer.
まあまあ もうしばらく
あとしばらくお待ちを
ヘヘ　もう少し
Just a little more.
Cut the shit, Kaiji!
いい加減にしろ 悪ふざけは
I'm pulling that shit down!
こんな物 剥がせ
No way!
ウソだろ
何だよ これは
What's going on!?
どうして こんなことが
How did that happen!?
カイジ
Kaiji!
Kaiji...
カイジ…
ああ 頃合だからな
必然 こうなる
It was about time for this to happen.
う… なぜ　なぜ
Why!?
なぜ
This is impossible!
こんな こんなバカな
え？何？
さあ…
What's happening!?
Dunno.
What's going on!?
何が起きてんの？
分かんないよ
I don't know!
I dunno, but it's something big!
でも何か盛り上がってるぞ
Why? Why!? Why are they full of balls!?
なぜ なぜ　どうして玉があふれる
Both of them, the first and the second!
１段目も ２段目も
Why aren't they singing into the loser holes!?
なぜ沈まない ハズレ穴に
The loser holes are filled with pachinko balls!
パチンコ玉でハズレ穴が
詰まってる
あ… どういうこと
何それ
How!?
What's going on!?
But there's something that's going to surprise you.
びっくりするぜ たぶん
え？
The other thing this double tilt has caused.
二重の奥への傾斜がもたらした
もう１つの現象
Once you see it...
そいつを目の当たりにしたら
It's clogged with balls!
玉が詰まる
That's what he meant!
これが奴の言う その現象
How did this happen!?
しかし なぜそんなことが
None are coming out of the trays' discharge tubes!
で… 出ない
クルーンのハズレ玉が排出口から
But why!?
どうしてだ　なぜだ
Why? Why are none coming out!?
なぜ なぜ出ないんだ　どうして
Why!?
Did he clog them with something while playing!?
何か物を詰めたのか
この勝負の最中に
No... No no no!
いや… いやいやいや
Impossible!
そんなことは あり得ない
The other thing this double tilt has caused.
二重の奥への傾斜がもたらした
もう１つの現象
Double...
二重！奥…
Tilt... Since it's tilted so far back...
つまり手前への傾斜が奥へ
何てことだ
No! This can't be happening! Tilt it the other way!
逆だ　逆流だ
そう　まさにそれは想定外
Yes!
It was unexpected!
まったく想定外の出来事
Completely unexpected!
通常 沼は３段目のクルーンで
必ず外れるよう
Normally, the third tray is tilted forward so balls never make it to the winning hole in back!
奥の大当たりに玉が行かぬ
手前傾斜に設定されている
Normally, the third tray is tilted forward so balls never make it to the winning hole in back!
たとえクルーンが水平か
多少 奥への傾斜でも問題ない
Even if it's level, or tilted back, it should work fine!
しかし今回のような
過剰な奥への傾斜
But the Bog is now tilted back double,
一条がもたらしたマックスの
奥への傾斜と ビルの傾斜
both by the building and by Ichijou setting it to max!
この２つが重なった
過剰な奥傾斜は想定外
But with this double tilt, something unexpected happens!
結果 異変が生まれた
クルーンのハズレ玉の通路
The tubing to carry misses out of the trays!
その通路の玉を排出する
最後の道が
Its final segment is no longer sloped downward!
通常の下りではなく
その逆
Instead, it rises!
上りに 上りになってしまったのだ
Now it rises!
故に玉はこぼれない
Thus, the balls can't roll out!
こぼれずに たまっていく
Instead, they clog!
１段目 ２段目のハズレ玉は
次々 内部に蓄えられ
The balls from the first two trays rise inside the piping!
上っていく
まるで枝を上るシャクトリムシ
Like a caterpillar climbing a branch!
Little by little, little by little it climbs!
少しずつ少しずつ這い上がる
They pile up, reaching for the light!
光を求め積み重なる
そんな異変が実は着々と
この沼に起こっていたのだ
This has been happening within the Bog all this time!
そして数秒前 開花　塞いだのだ
And a few seconds ago, its effect began to show!
The paths to failure are blocked!
破滅 死に至る道を
すげえ
ホントにすげえ
Wow, that's amazing!
クルーンに送り込まれた玉は
もう死なない
The balls in the trays can no longer die!
Even falling in the loser hole, they return to life!
ハズレ穴に弾かれ 再び生を得る
よみがえる
They revive!
不死の玉たちは次第に
最下点である奥側に
The immortal balls roll to the lowest point!
ゆらゆらとたまり
そこに新玉
And then, a new ball hits!
新たに送り込まれた玉がぶつかる
A new ball hits them!
The shock scatters both the new ball and the revived ones!
その衝撃で新玉も再生玉も
わけの分からぬ乱反射
無軌道な動きとなり
クルーン内を漂う狂騒
They scatter randomly through the tray!
そしていつしか
そんな混乱混迷に疲れ
And then, tiring of their chaos,
休みを乞うように駆け込む
they fall into the winning hole as if seeking rest!
当たり穴へ
安息の地へ
To a new repose!
それが１段目で起こり
And soon, the spark lit in the first tray sets the second ablaze!
すぐその現象は２段目に飛び火
波及する
It's like a chain reaction!
すげえ 初めて見た　２発
Wow, I've never seen this happen before!
A second ball!
２発同時だぜ
Two at the same time!
カイジ
遠藤さん
Kaiji!
Endoh! Here we go!
いくぜ　７億取り
We're getting that 700 million!
決着の時
The decisive moment!
間に合わず
He is too late!
一条 懸命に自分のリモコンを操作
Ichijou pounds at his remote control!
奥への傾斜の方向を
手前の傾斜に戻したが
He sets it to tilt forward again!
間に合わず
But he is too late!
２両突入　牙城を撃つ戦車
Two tanks plunge forward into the enemy stronghold!
カイジ　２発だ
Kaiji!
You've got two in!
３段目に２発
Two balls in the third tray!
決まるよな　決まるよな これで
This is it! This is really it!
ああ 入るさ　入るに決まってる
Yeah! One is gonna make it in!
待ってたんだ
じっと長い時間 ２段目止まりで
I've been waiting to finally make it out of the second tray!
それを今 破った
Now I've broken through!
しかも２発同時　ここは入る
With two balls at once!
This time we'll win!
それが必然　それが勢い
It's going to happen! It has to happen!
入る　ここは入る
One's gonna make it in!
南無 南無 南無…
カイジと遠藤
２人の祈りを乗せた銀玉は
The balls on which Kaiji and Endoh stake their hopes slow, and one falls!
やがて回転する力を失い
１つはハズレ穴へ
が 残る１つは かいくぐった
The remaining ball slips through a gap!
ハズレ穴とハズレ穴の
危い隙間を這い上がり
Slips through a gap between two losing holes!
７億の穴へ
Toward the 700-million-yen hole!
う… いけ！
Go!
カイジ
Kaiji!
大丈夫　大丈夫 まだある
Don't worry! We still have a chance!
２の矢　３の矢
A second shot! A third shot!
行った また３段目に
There! He's back to the third tray!
すげえ　何だ こりゃ
突っ込み放題だ
I can't believe it!
He keeps slipping them through!
ダメだ　もうダメだ
I can't take this anymore!
カイジ　すげえ
正解だったぜ お前に乗って
Kaiji! You were right!
３分　３分はいけるはずだ
Three minutes! I have three more minutes!
３分間は排出口の最後の直線
Three more minutes with the end of the discharge tubes tilted backward!
その傾きは
奥へ倒れたままのはずだ
玉は排出されない
穴は詰まったまま
Three minutes with it clogged up...
１段目 ２段目の
ハズレ穴なしの状態が続く
Three minutes with the first and second tray loser holes clogged!
すぐには戻らない
It can't go back immediately!
奥への過剰な傾斜が
玉詰まりの原因と知った一条は
Even if Ichijou tilts the Bog back to the front...
すぐ手前向きの
傾斜へと沼を操作しただろうが
５秒や10秒じゃ無理
He can't do it in a matter of seconds!
露骨に傾斜がチェンジされちゃ
If he's that obvious about it, everyone will notice!
打ち手に
その変化が気づかれかねない
だから この台は そういう操作を
しても ゆっくり気づかれぬように
So no matter what he does with the remote, it'll tilt slowly!
It'll move little by little, so no one notices!
ごく少しずつしか
変化してくれない
裏目だ
その用心深い設定が裏目　命取り
Its cautious setup is backfiring on him!
A fatal flaw!
いっぺんに３つ ３段目
Three balls in the third tray at once!
ヘッ　きたぜ 一条
This is it, Ichijou!
破滅の時　お前が敗れる時
This is the end! You're finished!
は… ダメだ　もうダメ
I can't take this anymore!
奥への傾斜は すぐ直らない
どんなに早くても２～３分
It won't tilt forward again! The fastest it can possibly go will take two or three minutes!
その間 ハズレ続けるなんて
あり得ない
There's no way he'll keep missing that long!
だ… 大丈夫かも
Don't worry!
We can make it through this!
しのげるかもしれない
あ？
アクシデントがなければ
As long as there aren't any accidents...
何？何だ どういうことだ？
What!? What do you mean!?
言ってみろ 大丈夫とは？
What do you mean, "don't worry"!?
傾向があるんです ある傾向が
There's a slight tilt...
Go for it!
何？
What!?
恐らくは そういうことでは？
So...
な… 何てことだ
I can't believe it!
なら なら あり得るのか
This... This means...
This just might work!
玉と玉がぶつかるような
アクシデント
Without accidents like balls touching...
それさえなければ あり得る
全部ハズレも
Without that, we can make it through!
They'll all fall out!
いけ！
まだ２つ残ってるぞ
Go for it!
You've still got two left!
２つ ２つ…
Two! Two! Two!
その熱気 狂騒に押されるように
The balls pass through, as if driven by that passion!
通過する　またも
Again!
ハズレ穴とハズレ穴の隙間を
Again, they slip between two loser holes!
その関門を抜ける　しかも２玉
This time, it's two balls!
相次ぎ通過
One following the other!
急降下　最下点へ
They dive toward the target!
爆撃
They divebomb!
焼くは本丸　決着の城
Their target, the inner citadel!
成就
They're fulfilled!
満願成就
His prayers are fulfilled!
いけ！
Go!
ああ　いけ！
くく…
Go!
えー
何？
What!?
だ… 大丈夫だ
もういっちょある もういっちょ
Don't worry!
There's still one left! Go for it!
いけ！
なんで
どうして
Why!?
Why did it miss!?
なんで それる
いい所で左に
Why did it tilt left!?
か… カイジ
Kaiji!
水槽…
The water tanks...
ビルの南角の部屋に積んで
They're in a room on the south side of the building.
奥に倒した
They tilt the Bog back.
しかし… ああ！
But...
ううっ しくじった
致命傷か これは
I fucked it up!
Was that a fatal mistake!?
何だよ 致命傷って　カイジ
What do you mean "fatal", Kaiji!?
よれちまったんだ
何？
It's twisting!
What!?
奥に倒しゃ そのまま
素直に入るかと思ったら
I thought if I tilted it back they'd roll straight in...
わずかなヨレ
ミスを許さず あらがってきた
But there's just a little twist in to keep that from happening!
身をよじって
It's twisted!
当たりを防ぎにきた
機械のくせに
This damn machine is twisted to make sure no one wins!
悪魔だ　こいつはやっぱり
It really is a demon!
食い殺される
It's swallowing me whole!
最後の 最後の 最後の土壇場
In the final, final, final moment!
牙をむく沼　逆襲 逆襲
The Bog bares its fangs and counterattacks! Counterattacks!
人食い沼の逆襲
the Man-eating Bog counterattacks!
Proverbs of Kaiji Returns!
Heaven places no man above another, no man below another!
What I'm going on about is that the rise and fall of men is chance alone!
Even a fool or scum has a chance to win!